Guide to the North American Indian art: ephemeral publications about individual artists; also including some original artwork, ca. 1950-1980
Department of Special Collections
North American Indian art: ephemeral publications about individual artists; also including some original artwork,
ca. 1950-1980
Special Collections M0977
Carpenter, Edwin H., collector.
2.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1997.
Scope and Content
Areas represented include Canada, the Great Plains, East (U.S.), West (U.S.), and New Southwest.
Access Terms
Art, Modern--20th century.; Indians of North America--Art.
Container List
- General
  - Correspondence to Edwin H. Carpenter, Jamake Highwater 1970, 1984, (1 letter, 1 card) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous notes on Indian life [1970s?], (21 notes) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Acknowledgment (book) to Edwin H. Carpenter 1984, (2 sheets, 1 note) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Partial book manuscript, unknown author (64 pp.) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Multitribal
  - Program, "2nd Annual Los Angeles Indian Fair," 1967, (22 p, 1 note) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Indian Historian, Winter. San Francisco. 1970, (67 pp.) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Wee Wish Tree, November. San Francisco 1971, (42 pp.) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Nimrod, Spring/Summer. University of Tulsa 1972, (42 pp.) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Exhibit Announcement 1980, (2 sheets) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Plains Region
  - "Plains Indian Painting," The American West, Palo Alto, CA, pp.4-15, 74-75. Howling Wolf, Oscar Howe, Archie Blackowl, Sitting Bull March 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Goble, Paul (Blackfoot), Booklist, Bradbury Press. 1983, (2 sheets, 1 note) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Reiss, Winold (Blackfoot). (6 color illustrations) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Des Jarliat, Patrick (Chippewa). 1947, (1 B/W illustration) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Art of the Cherokee." n.d., (magazine clip, 2 pp) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Beeler, Joe (Cherokee). n.d., (2 notes) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Golsh, Larry (Cherokee). Exhibit Announcement 1976, (1 p, B/W portrait) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Seabourn, Bert D. (Cherokee) Exhibit Announcement. [1997?], (1 color & 2 B/W illustrations, portrait.) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Waano-Gano, Joseph (Cherokee). 1965, (2 news clips with 1 portrait and biography) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Howling Wolf (Cheyenne). Book Announcement. n.d., (4 color illustrations, text, 1 card, 1 envelope) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - West, Richard (Cheyenne) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Booklist (cover color, illustration) nd
    - Magazine illustration (color) with note. 1972
  - Davis, Jesse (Comanche) 1964/65 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Oklahoma Today Winter (2 color illustraionts)
  - Nevaquaya, Doc Tate (Comanche) 1973,1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - American Indian, February (pages 12-13 and B/W cover illustration ). Program, Intertribal Ceremonial, Gallup, (1 color illustration)
  - Riddles, Leonard (Comanche) 1942 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Christian Science Monitor, February., (1 news clip with B/W illustration)
  - Slump, Sarain (Cree-Shoshone) 1970-1972, (1 news clip with B/W illustration, 2 notes) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Beaver, Fred (Creek) 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Oklahoma Today, Winter, (1 color illustration, dated 1948)
  - Deere, Noah (Creek) n.d., (1 magazine illustration, color) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Tiger, Jerome (Creek-Seminole) 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Book Announcement and booklist, University of Oklahoma Press., (18 pp ,2 color illustrations.)
  - Red Star, Kevin (Crow) [1979?], (2 color illustrations.) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Early Kiowa Art." 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Oklahoma Today, winter., (Text & color illustrations, 5 pages)
  - Big Bow, Woody (Tse Ko Yata) (Kiowa) [1960?] &1970, (2 color illustrations) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bosin, Blackbear (Kiowa-Comanche) 1960,1970, (3 color illustrations and text, 1 B/W magazine cover illustration.) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Hill, Bobby (White Buffalo) (Kiowa-Apache) 1968 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Frontier Times, January., (1 color cover illustration)
  - Momaday, Al (Kiowa) 1963,1981, (1 B/W magazine illustration, 1 news clip) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Mopope, Stephen (Kiowa) 1978-1979, (3 color illustrations, 1 B/W illustration) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Tsa Toke, Monroe (Kiowa) Book announcement, "The Peyote Ritual," Grabhorn Press. nd, 1944, (Biographical note with 2 B/W illustrations.) (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Williams, Dave (Tos-que) (Kiowa) 1965 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Program, 6th Annual Pow Wow, Saugus, California., (2 B/W cover illustrations)
  - Nighthawk (Iroquois) (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Many Smokes, summer 1968., (1 color cover illustration)
  - Two Arrows, Tom (Iroquois). 1953-1965, (10 color illustrations, 2 new clips with portrait, and 1 B/W illustrations.) (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Cochran, George McKee (Osage-Cherokee) [1973?], (2 color & 2 B/W illustrations, biography.) (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Pahsetopah, Loren (Osage) 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Oklahoma Today, winter., (1 color illustration, dated 1963)
  - English, Sam [Plains ?] 1986 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Booklist, University of New Mexico Press., (1 color & 1 B/W illustration, dated 1985.)
  - Echohawk, Brummett (Pawnee) 1959 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - True West, December 1965, (1 color cover illustration).
    - Oklahoma Today, Spring., (5 B/W illustrations).
    - One biographical note and postcard
  - Jake, Alvin (Pawnee) 1956, (1 B/W illustration) (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Crumbo, Woodrow (Potawatomie), 1940, (2 b/w illustrations and l biography) (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Bad Heart Bull, Amos (Sioux) 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Book announcement and booklist,. Pictographic History of the Oglala Sioux, 1890-1913., 1 color & 2 B/W illustrations
  - Dupree, William (Sioux) 1955, (1 color illustration) (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Larvie, Calvin (Sioux) nd, (1 color illustration) (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Howe, Oscar (Sioux). 1941, (1 news clip with b/w illustration) (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Kicking Bear (Sioux) The Master Key, September 1935, (1 b/w illustration, dated 1885.) (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Sitting Bull (Sioux) "Sitting Bull's Picture Story," True West, 1960 August., (4 b/w sketches, [~1870?] (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Southwest Region
  - "American Inter-Tribal Indian Art," Art & Archeology, 1931 November-December., (pages 147-59, b/w illustrations.) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Ma-Pe-Wei, Awa-Tsireh, Hokeah, Agua-Pi, Fred Kobatie, Tse-Ye-Mu, Quah-Ah [Tonita Pena]
  - Catalog, Philbrook Annual Exhibit. American Indian Painting, 1947, (12 pages, B/W illustrations) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Gilbert Atencio, Harrison Begay, Allan Houser, Percy Sandy, Pablita Velarde, Patrick DesJarlait, Blackbear Bosin, Oscar Howe, George Keahbone, Quincey Tahoma, Richard West, Joe Herrra, others.
  - "Contemporary Indian Art," Arizona Highways, 1950 February, ( pp.12, 26-29, b/w illustrations). (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Modern Navajo Watercolor Painting," Arizona Highways, July 1956 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    (pp.12, 26-29, color & b/w illustrations.) Beatien Yazz, Quincy Tahoma, Gerald Nailor, Harrison Begay, Narcisco Abeyta, Andy Tishnahjinnie, Stanley Batisse
  - "Indian Painters Museum," Indian Life [Month?] 1959, (9 pp.26-31, color & b/w illustrations) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Pablita Velarde, Quincy Tahoma, Gilbert Atencio, Philbrook Museum.
  - "Indian Paintings," New Mexico Magazine, December. 1960, (pp. 38-43, color & b/w illustrations) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Joe Herrera, Quah-Ah, Anthony Da, Harrison Begay.
  - Arizona Highways, August. (color illustrations) 1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Harrison Begay, Stanley Batisse, Wayne Yazzi, Beatien Yazz
  - Book Announcement, American Indian Painting, (by Dorothy Dunn ). 1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Color illustrations by: Ruth Watchman, Eva Mirabal, Kylsdewa, George Keahbone, Wesley Nash, Fred Kaboti, Big Lefthand, Nehaklie.
  - Booklist, Northland Press. 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Multiple Western & South-Western subjects, including southwestern painters. (20 pp.)
  - Dewey, Wilson (Apache) n.d., (1 color magazine illustration). (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Houser (also Hauser), Allan (Apache). 1937-1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - El Palacio Magazine, 1937
    - Arizona Highways, 1950
    - Desert Magazine (March 1955)
    - Oklahoma Today, Winter, 1964/65., (color & b/w illustrations.)
    - Published illustrations, 1940 & 1953.
    - New clips, n.d., (1 b/w illustration.)
  - Stevens, Jim (Apache), "Apache Artist in Pimaland," Arizona Highways, 1963 October, (pp. 40-45, b/w illustrations & portrait) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Navajo's Art Gains Attention," 1965, (l news clip) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Navajo Original Art [?], unsigned and undated, on card stock, nd, (11 cards, 2" x 3") (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Abeyta, Narcisco (Navajo) Arizona Highways, July 1956, (1 color illustration) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Austin, Frank (Bahah Zhonie) (Navajo) n.d., (5 color illustrations) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Batisse, Stanley (Navajo) Arizona Highways, July 1956, (2 b/w and 2 color illustrations) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Begay, Harrison (Navajo). 1950-1957, (2 color illustrations, 1 portrait, 1950) (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "Harrison Begay - Navajo Artist," Desert Magazine
    - December, 1957, pp. 13-15.
  - Begay, Harrison (Navajo). [1950?], (6 mounted silkscreen prints (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Indian dancers.)
  - Begay, Harrison (Navajo). [1950?], (10 mounted silckscreen prints -- (Box 2, Folder 20)
    figures and animals.)
  - Begay, Harrison (Navajo) 1950-1980, (12 cards with color illustrations, 6 magazine clips with color illustrations.) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Chee, Robert (Navajo). Arizona Highways, August. 1961, (2 color illustrations). (Box 2, Folder 22)
    See also Box 5, Folders 4 and 5.
  - Denetsosie, Hoke (Navajo), 1952 & nd (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - "Hoke Denetsosie-Navajo Artist," Desert Magazine, July, pp.12-15, (1 b/w illustration plus portrait.)
    - (1 news clip with b/w illustration.)
  - Dodge, Adee (Navajo), Arizona Highways, July and August 1959, (2 color illustrations) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Edward, Carl (Navajo) Arizona Highways, December 1948, (1 color illustration) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Gorman, Carl N. (Navajo). (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Westways, August 1962, (color cover illustration)
    - Exhibit Announcement (1 portrait) 1970
  - Kahn, Chester (Tsa Zazzy) (Navajo) Booklist, Naturgraph Books, nd, (1 cover illlustration) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - King, James (Navajo) Arizona Highways, September 1978, (Back cover, cover illustration) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Lee, Charlie (Navajo) 1940s-50s, (15 color & b/w magazine and notecard illustrations) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Nailor, Gerald (Navajo) [1950?], (5 color and b/w magazine illustrations) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Nailor, Gerald (Navajo) 1951, (2 mounted silkscreen prints) (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Naranjo, Adolf (Navajo). Atlantic Monthly, June 1959, (1 color cover illustration) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Notay, Ed Lee (Navajo). 1956, (1 color cover illustration) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Paladin, Chetlahe (Navajo [?]) 1972, (1 color illustration, 1 note) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Salt, Freddie (Navajo) New Mexico Wildlife, November/December1962, (1 color cover illustration) (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Shirley, Charles Keatsie (Navajo) 1940s-1950s, (8 b/w and 1 color magazine illustrations, plus 1 note) (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Tahoma, Quincy (Navajo) n.d., (1 color magazine illustration) (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Tilden, Bennie (Navajo) n.d., (1 color magazine illustration) (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Tsihnahjinnie, Andy (Navajo) 1950s-1960s, (9 color & 2 B/W magazine illustrations, 2 book announcements) (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Tshihnahjinnie, Andy (Navajo). Calendar, 1971, (13 b/w illustrations) (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Vigil, Frank [Navajo?]. n.d., (4 mounted silkscreen prints) (Box 2, Folder 41)
    See also Box 5, Folder 7
  - Navajo Children's Art 1977, (1 news clip) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Yazz, Beatien (Jimmy Toddy) (Navajo) n.d., (3 mounted silkscreen prints.) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Yazz, Beatien (Navajo) 1950's, (7 magazine color illustrations, 2 b/w portraits with biographical text; 6 illustrated notecards.) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "At One With the Gods," [artist: Hosteen Clah, Navajo?] Indian Life [Month/Year?] pp. 3-5 n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - New Mexico Indians Pocket Handbook, New Mexico Association on Indian Affairs, Santa Fe 1948, (96 pp.) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Jose Rey Toledo, Velino Herrera, Harrison Begay. Eva Mirabal.
  - "America's First Painters" National Geographic, 1955, March. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    (7 pp.) Ma-Pe-Wi, Pablita Velarde, Fred Kabotie, Joe Herrera, Quah Ah, Gerald Nailor, Harrison Begay, Bennie Tilden, F. Blackbear BosinCalvin Larvie, Noah Deere, W. Richard West, Dorothy Dunn, Oliver LaFarge. Philbrook Museum.
  - Atencio, Gilbert. (Pueblo-San Ildefonso). 1940s-1950s, (1 color magazine illustration, 3 color illustrated notecards.) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bear, Michael (Pueblo) n.d., (1 color illustration) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Chalee, Pop (Blue Flower) (Pueblo-Taos) [1950s?], (2 silkscreen color prints) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Chalee, Pop (Pueblo-Taos). [1950s?] (Box 3, Folder 9)
    (2 magazine illustrations, 1 color, 1 b/w portrait)
  - Garcia, Lorenzo (Pueblo-Santo Domingo). National Geographic, 1955 March., (1 color magazine illustration). (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Gobin, Henry (Pueblo). 1962 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - New Mexico Wildlife, May/June 1951., (1 cover color illustration)
  - Hardin, Helen (Pueblo) 2 Exhibit Announcements, 1980 and 1987, (2 color illustrations, [1980s?].) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Herrera, Joe H. (Pueblo-Cochiti). 1949-1955 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - "Dancing Indians Are His Subjects." Desert Magazine, pp.15-17, August 1949., (2 b/w illustrations, including portrait.)
    - Arizona Highways & National Geographic. 1950 and 1955., (2 color illustrations)
      See also Box 5, Folder 3.
  - Herrera, Velino (Ma-Pe-Wi) (Pueblo-Zia) 1931,1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Los Angeles Times, 1931., (2 news clips)
    - Christian Science Monitor, 1967., (news clip with b/w illustration and 1 portait.)
  - Herrera, Velino (Pueblo-Zia) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - New Mexico Magazine, January 1932, pp.24-25 (2 b/w magazine illustrations.)
    - Desert Magazine, July 1948, (1 b/w illustration p.9)
  - Herrera, Velino (Pueblo-Zia) [1950s-1960s], (4 color magazine illustrations, 1 color notecard illustration) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Mirabal, Vicente (Pueblo-Taos) Arizona Highways, August 1952, (1 color magazine illustration.) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Montoya, Geronima (Po-Tsunu) (Pueblo-San Juan). 1966 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - The Quarterly of the Southwestern Association on Indian Affairs, Inc. Winter. pp 14-16. (2 b/w magazine illustrations.)
  - Peña Encarnacion (Pueblo-San Ildefonso) "Man of Three Names," Desert Magazine, July, pp 18-19. 1959, (1 b/w portrait.) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Peña Tonita (Pueblo-Cochiti). Desert Magazine, 1959 November., (1 b/w magazine illustration.) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    See also Box 2, Folder 6; Box 3, Folder 5; and M260: Thomas Family Papers, Box 1, Folder 23.
  - Quintana, Ben (Pueblo-Cochiti) 1952 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Arizona Highways, August 1952, (2 color magazine illustrations.)
    - Indians at Work, January 1952, (1 b/w illustration, biographical text.)
  - Sanchez, Abel (Pueblo). Quarterly of the Southwestern Association on Indian Affairs, Inc., 1966 Winter., pp. 10-12. (1 b/w portrait, 1 b/w illustration.) (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Scholder, Fritz (Pueblo). Portfolio Announcement, 1975 February., (10 b/w illustrations.) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Speckled Rock, Paul (Pueblo-Santa Clara). n.d., (2 color illustrated notecards, biographical text.) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Taos Indian Children Art Book. Book Announcement. [1971?], (1 letter, 1 note, 2 envelopes.) (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Toledo, Jose Rey (Pueblo-Jamez). Arizona Highways, February, 1950, & August, 1952., (2 color illustrations.) (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Tsireh, Amos. (Pueblo-[Izuni?]). 1950s (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Arizona Highways, August 1952., (1 color illustration.)
    - Desert Magazine, November 1959., (1 b/w illustration.)
  - Velarde, Pablita (Santa Clara). 1955-1965 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - New Mexico Magazine, December, 1960., (2 b/w illustrations.)
    - Indian Life, August 1961, pp. 23-26. (story, biography, portrait, color illustrations.)
    - Desert Magazine, September, 1956, pp. 24-26. (2 b/w illustrations, w/ portrait, magazine article w/ portrait.)
    - Book Announcement. 1960, (1 b/w illustration.)
    - Oklahoma Today, Winter 1964/65, (1 b/w illustration.)
  - Velarde, Pablita (Pueblo, Santa Clara.) 1960s (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - San Diego Union, December 5, 1960.
    - Christian Science Monitor, June 29, 1965., (2 news clips, 4 b/w illustrations.)
  - Warm Mountain (Pueblo) 1957 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Los Angeles Times, 1957 June 3., (1 news clip.)
      Vincent Price.
  - Chizomana Blind Maiden (Hopi). Los Angeles Times, 1975 July 18., (news clip, 2 b/w illustrations.) (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - David, Neil, Sr. (Hopi). Book announcement. 1974, (1 b/w illustration.) (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Kabotie, Fred (Hopi). (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - National Geographic, 1955 March, (1 color illustration & note.)
    - Handlist of Kabotie works, Southwest Museum, 1966, (1 page.)
    - Booklist, Northland Press, 1977 Autumn., (1 color cover & 1 b/w illustration & note.)
  - Kabotie, Michael (Hopi). Arizona Highways, 1956 August., (2 color illustrations.) (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Loloma, Charles (Hopi). Arizona Highways, 1959 May, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    pp. 34-36. (1 b/w portrait.)
  - Mootzka, W. (Hopi). Desert Magazine, 1939 December., (1 b/w illustration.) (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Naha, Raymond (Hopi). Arizona Highways, 1966 August., (2 color illustrations.) (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Numkena, Lewis, Jr. (Hopi). Arizona Highways, 1950, (1 color illustration.) (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Parrot, Sikyatki (Hopi). National Geographic. n.d., (1 color illustration & note.) (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Preston, Robert (Temak) (Hopi). Program, All Indian Pow Wow, July, 1959, (1 color cover illustration.) (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Shelton, Peter (Hopi). Oklahoma Today, 1964/65 Winter., (1 b/w illustration.) (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Tovehaema, Kyrat (Hopi). 1981, (6 illustrated notecards, b/w. 1940s. 1 advertising note.) (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Medina, Raphael (Zuñi). Los Angeles County advertising brochure. 1977, (1 color illustration.) (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Sandy, Percy (Kai-SA) (Zuñi). n.d., (4 mounted silk screen prints.) (Box 3, Folder 44)
    See also Box 5, Folder 9.
  - Seowtewa, Alex (Zuñi). New Mexico Magazine, "Michaelangelo of the Southwest."p.p 20-25. 1977 June., (8 color illustrations, 1 portrait.) (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Shebala, Dixon (Zuñi). 1962-1964, (12 illustrated color notecards and 1 note.) (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - The Master Key, April-June 1963, (1 b/w cover illustration. California Indian Photograph reproduction.) (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Sauvel, Allen (Cabùilla). 1970, (1 b/w illustration, news clipping.) (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Galvan, Philip (Ohlone). The Indian Historian, January and October. 1966, (2 color illustrations.) (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Stan-Padilla, Viento (Yaqui). Book announcement. n.d., (1 b/w illustration.) (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Versh, Esther (Yaqui). n.d., (2 color illustrations.) (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Blake, George (Yurok-Hupa). 1976, (news clipping, 1 b/w illustration.) (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - California Indian Children's Art - Advertisement. 1973, (2 pages, incl.6 color illustrations.) (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Exhibition Announcement. "The Other Southwest," Indian Arts and Crafts of Northwestern Mexico, The Heard Museum. 1977, (2 pages.) (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Canadian Eskimo Art, Pamphlet, Dept. of Northern Affairs & National Resources, Ottawa, Canada. 1955, (40 pages.) (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - "Land of the Lively Art," Reprint, The Beaver, Autumn, Hudson's Bay Company. 1961, (6 pages.) (Box 3, Folder 56)
    Minqitok, Mary Pitseoluk, Kenojuak, Nepachee.
  - "Indian Art of the Northwest Coast," Exhibition Announcement. 1962, (1 b/w sketch.) (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - "Eskimo Graphic Art," Exhibit Announcement. 1968, (2 pages, 1 illustration.) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Old Time Recipes of Manitoba Indians, Pamphlet. 1971, (5 pages with sketches.) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Cape Dorset Prints," The Beaver, Spring, p.p. 22-31. 1975, (color & b/w sketches with text.) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Luktak, Kenojuak, Pitseola[u?]k, Niviaksiak, Kananqinak, Eeqyvudhuk.
  - Contemporary Native Art of Alaska, Exhibit Announcement. Archorage Historical & Fine Arts Museum. 1979, (17 pages.) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Contemporary Indian and Inuit Art of Canada. Department of Indian Affairs and Northern Development. Ottawa, Canada. 1983, (29 pages & 1 page list of artists.) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Eskimo Graphics. Engagement Calendar. 1983, (43 pages, 50 color & b/w illustrations.) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Cree Artist, unknown. [1970?], (1 b/w illustration on notecard.) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - [Fonseca, Harry?] (Maidu). [1980?], (1 postcard with b/w illustration.) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Aehevak,Kenojuak. 1980, (news clip with 1 b/w illustration.) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - James, Allen (Kwakiutl). n.d., (8 color illustrations on notecards.) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Eliyakota (Inuit). [1978?], (newsclip with 1 b/w illustration.) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Munoz, Rie (Inuit). Booklist, Alaska Northwest Publishing Company. 1984, (1 color illustration.) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "Artctic Life," Unicef Bulletin, Vol. 9, No. 3, p.p. 4-5. 1961, (5 b/w illustrations, 3 portraits.) (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Munqituk, Niviaksiak, Kananqinak.
  - Canadian Stamp, with Inuit design. 1979, (1 stamp on envelope.) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Cape Dorset Calendar. 1979, (13 color illustrations, multiple artists.) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Pitaloosie, Vamasic, Kananqinak, Kenojuak, Eeqyudluk.
  - "Coin News." 1990, (1 news clip, Canadian.) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "Musk Ox Ruminations." Life Magazine, Vol. 5 No. 5, May 1985, p.p 95-110. (14 color magazine illustrations by various Inuit artists.) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Pueblo ceremonial, fusures on wood. n.d., (5 illustrations on wood veneer postcards.) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Herrera, Joe (Pueblo-Cochiti). [Possibly attributable to Gilbert Atencio (Pueblo-Cochiti).]. Sunday Evening Post. n.d., (2 color magazine illustrations.) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Chee, Robert (Navajo). ca. 1960, (3 silkscreen prints, 10 x 12.) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Chee, Robert (Navajo). ca. 1960, (3 silkscreen prints, 12 x 14.) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Honawa, Kacha (White Bear) (Hopi). 1964 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Notecards 1964, (12 notecards with color illustrations.)
    - "The Niman Ceremony," 1959
    - Arizona Highways, July 1959, pp. 16-28. (3 color and 6 b/w illustrations.)
  - Vigil, Frank [Apache or Navajo?] [1960s-70s?], (1 silkscreen print, 14 x 17.) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Qua' Huah [Pueblo?] n.d., (1 original watercolor, 12 x 15.) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Sandy, Percy (Zuñi). [1950s-60s?], (2 silkscreen prints, 10 x 12.) (Box 5, Folder 9)